EDWIN RISVIANTO

Yogyakarta, ID · +6285155022840 erisvianto@gmail.com · LinkedIn: Edwin Risvianto · Github: Risviantoe

Graduated with Diploma in Informatics Engineering majoring in web development from Amikom University Yogyakarta with a Cumulative GPA of 3.89/4. Have passion and interest in Frontend Developer. In the same field, I have approximately 1 year of internship experience at GCM Foundation and PT. Media Kreasi Abadi as Frontend Developer. Able to use React JS, Typescript, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Sass, and Git.

EXPERIENCE

FEB 2022 - JUL 2022

FRONTEND DEVELOPER - INTERNSHIP, PT MEDIA KREASI ABADI

- Responsible for brainstorming, developing, testing, collaborating, code reviewing, deploying, bug bashing, and launching frontend feature in a team. (React, Typescript, CSS, Context API).
- Ensure the technical feasibility of UI/UX design.
- Lead and assign tasks to the team so that the work can be completed according to the target time. (Microsoft Planner)
- Integrate the API that has been created by the backend division so that the website can be used functionally. (Axios)
- Pitching to stakeholders and mentors.

JAN 2022 - JUL 2022

BACKEND DEVELOPER - PART TIME, GCM FOUNDATION

- Develop an online exam website with various types of questions and answers. (Laravel)
- Ensure the technical feasibility of UI/UX design and define tasks to delegate to other engineers.
- Designing the API as needed to be consumed on the frontend.
- Integrate the API on the frontend to make it work as intended. (React, Axios)

SEP 2021 – JAN 2022

FRONTEND DEVELOPER – INTERNSHIP, GCM FOUNDATION

- Design the login page according to the briefing by the company CEO. (Figma).
- Developing authentication systems on various blended learning websites under the auspices of Geschool. (React, Bootstrap)

AUG 2018 - AUG 2019

FIBER OPTIC TECHNICAL SUPPORT - FULL TIME, PT. JEMBATAN CITRA

NUSANTARA

- Conduct a site survey of prospective clients to ensure that prospective clients are within the coverage of the company's fiber optic network and provide details of the requirements needed for installation to make it easier for sales to calculate the required costs.
- Provide an overview to the installer regarding the location of potential clients to facilitate the installation process.

- Successful installation of internet network over 50 new clients.
- Maintain service quality by performing network maintenance to maintain client comfort and satisfaction.

EDUCATION

OCT 2022

DIPLOMA OF INFORMATICS ENGINEERING, UNIVERSITAS AMIKOM YOGYAKATA

Cumulative GPA: 3.89/4.0 | Focus on majoring in Web Development.

JUL 2018

COMPUTER AND NETWORK ENGINEERING, SMK N 1 BANTUL

SKILLS

- HTML/CSS
- Javascript
- Typescript
- React Js
- Laravel

- Tailwind CSS
- Bootstrap
- SASS
- Git

ORGANIZATION EXPERIENCE

2020 - NOW

IKATAN MUDA MUDI MERTOSANAN KULON

TREASURER

• Provide maximum impact in the implementation of work programs by accelerating transparent and effective budget distribution.

2020 - 2021

HIMPUNAN MAHASISWA DIPLOMA INFORMATIKA

VICE CHAIRMAN

• Responsible for coordinating the division coordinator and replacing the chairman's duties when absent.

2020 - 2021

IKATAN MAHASISWA BIDIKMISI AMIKOM

MEMBER OF THE SOCIAL DIVISION

• Take an active role in community service by collaborating directly with many parties.